[
    {
        "front": "おばえます ❘❘",
        "back": "memorize",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "わすれます ❘❘",
        "back": "forgot",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "かちます",
        "back": "win",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "なくします ❘",
        "back": "lose",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "だします ❘ \n[レポートを～]",
        "back": "hand in [a report]",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "はらいます ❘",
        "back": "pay",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "かえします ❘",
        "back": "giveback, return",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "でかけます ❘❘",
        "back": "go out",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ぬぎます ❘",
        "back": "take off (clothes, shoes, etc.)",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "もっていきます ❘",
        "back": "take (something)",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "もってきます ❘❘❘",
        "back": "bring (something)",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "しんぱいます ❘❘❘",
        "back": "worry",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ざんぎょうします ❘❘❘",
        "back": "work overtime",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "しゅっちょうします ❘❘❘",
        "back": "go on a business trip",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "のみます ❘\n[くすり～]",
        "back": "take [medicine]",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "はいります ❘\n[おふろに～]",
        "back": "take [bath]",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "たいせつ [な]",
        "back": "important, precious",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "だいじょうぶ [な]",
        "back": "all right",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "あぶない",
        "back": "dangerous",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "もんだい",
        "back": "question, problem, trouble",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "こたえ",
        "back": "answer",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "きんえん",
        "back": "no smoking",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "けんこう ほけんしょう",
        "back": "[health] insurance card",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "かぜ",
        "back": "cold, flu",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ねつ",
        "back": "fever",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "びょうき",
        "back": "illness, disease",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "くすり",
        "back": "medicine",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "おふろ",
        "back": "bath",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "うわぎ",
        "back": "jacket, outerwear",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "したぎ",
        "back": "under wear",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "せんせい",
        "back": "doctor (used when addressing a medical doctor)",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "２、３ にち",
        "back": "2, 3 days (a few days)",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "２、３～",
        "back": "a few ~",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "～までに",
        "back": "before~, by~ (indicating time limit)",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "ですから",
        "back": "therefore, so",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "どうしましたか",
        "back": "what’s the matter?",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "いたいです",
        "back": "(I) have a pain [in my ~]",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "のど",
        "back": "throat",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    },
    {
        "front": "おだいじに",
        "back": "Take care of yourself. (said to the people who are ill)",
        "chapter": "N5 C17"
    }
]